Guide to the Yale Objects Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Yale objects collection, 1697-2002; Series I
  - #1160 Blue and white Yale banner, linen, circa 1927 (Box 197)
  - #1161 Pair of handmade linen dormitory curtains, with patterns used by Jessie P. Anderson, circa 1927 (Box 197)
  - #1162 Eta Phi symbol embroidered with gold thread on black velvet, circa 1900 (Box 181)
  - #1163 Class of 1879 flag. Blue cambric with painted "79" in white, circa 1879 (Box 203)
  - #1164 Three-handled silver loving cup presented to Thomas C. Shepard by the members of the Yale College Glee Club, 1903 (Box 204)
  - #1165 Beige silk crew-necked jersey with blue "Y" on front, circa 1896 (Box 205)
  - #1166 Blue blazer patch, circa 1896 (Box 205)
  - #1167 Blue Crew cap with crossed oars and "97" on front (Box 205)
  - #1168 Beige Crew Cap with "Y" and "BUC" on front (Box 205)
  - #1169 Memorabilia from the "and for Yale" capital fund raising campaign, 1994-1997 (Box 206)
  - #1170 Memorabilia from the "and for Yale" capital fund raising campaign, 1994 (Box 206)
  - #1171 Glass from the sesquicentennial celebration of the Graduate School (1997) (Box 207)
  - #1172 Crew jersey belonging to Willis H. Satterthwaite, Y. 1928, circa 1928 (Box 208)
  - #1173 Anatomical drawings (intended to be hung on a wall) in rolls (4) used for teaching life sciences at Yale, circa 1890 (Box 312)
  - #1174 Reunion banner for the class of 1930 (blue and white burlap), circa 1960 (Box 209)
  - #1175 Commencement (?) bannner with "1899", a gold facbric border, and gold fabric fringe, circa 1899 (Box 212)
  - #1176 China pitcher made by Avon Co. with painting of Yale football player by F. Earl Christy on one side and Yale seal on the other, circa 1905 (Box 210)
  - #1177 Ceramic mug with brown glaze inscribed "Yale. J. Earl Sheffield. '94" Other inscriptions including seal of "H BOYAH". "JES" inscribed on bottom, circa 1894 (Box 211)
  - #1178 Original Sterling Memorial Library door hardware, circa 1930 (Box 264)
  - #1179 Set of cards and uncut printed sheet celebrating Yale football's great players, teams, etc, 1998 (Box 192, Folder 3)
  - #1180 Blue long sleeve dress shirt with the inscription "Yale Undergraduate Comprehensivce Exhibition Jan 18-Jan 27", 1999 (Box 213)
  - #1181 Yale Bicentennial lapel pin, 1901 (Box 192, Folder 4)
  - #1182 Blue and white Wedgwood plates (12) with pictures of Yale buildings, 1931 (Box 215)
  - #1183 Blue yachting pennant bearing the name "Yale", circa 1928 (Box 214)
  - #1184 Two ski team patches, circa 1040 (Box 192, Folder 5)
  - #1185 Sterling silver cigarette case awarded to the Yale athletic Association, 1928 (Box 263)
  - #1186 Gold pocket-watch discovered within the walls of Calhoun College, undated (Box 255)
  - #1187 Southwest Teacher's College - photos and introduction, 1982 (Box 114B)
  - #1188 Blue and yellow CT special Olympics posters, 1995 (Box 174)
  - #1189 Sterling Memorial Library stained glass window, circa 1930 (Box 299)
  - #1190 Sterling Memorial Library pneumatic tube, circa 1930 (Box 299)
  - #1191 Scroll of Honor presented by the Yale Science and Engineering Association, 1976 (Box 275)
  - #1192 "Vat 69" bottle of scotch whiskey and Yale notebook, circa 1933, 1960 (Box 61)
  - #1193 "Once a Week" newspaper (Vol. 7, No. 17) with picture of Irene Coit (accepted at Yale) on cover, 1891 (Box 251, Folder 2)
  - #1194 Yale Street banner for the Special Olympics World Games Connecticut, 1995 (Box 174)
  - #1195 1929 Sheffield reunion banner with a "Y", 1954 (Box 175)
  - #1196 1929 Sheffield reunion banner with "Yale 1929 S", 1954 (Box 175)
  - #1198 Citation presented to Adeline DeLaurentis for participation in the Yale Pageant October 21, 1916 "held on the two hundredth anniversary of the removal of Yale College to New Haven" (Box 251, Folder 1)
  - #1199 Pillowcase of Ephraim Shill, circa 1909 (Box 265)
  - #1200 Class of 1879 class or reunion banner, undated (Box 252)
  - #1201 Yale Bowl ashtray by Lenox, and white Yale ashtray by W.C. Bunting (Box 272)
  - #1202 U.S. postage stamp collection depicting notable Yale men, undated (Box 269)
  - #1203 Sterling Silver cigarette case awarded by the Yale Athletic Association for the New Haven Horse Show, 1928 (Box 268)
  - #1204 Demitasse cup and saucer, circa 1900 (Box 256)
  - #1205 Mini Yale stein, circa 1900 (Box 256)
  - #1206 Signature blocks used for printed official documents, circa 1925-1992 (Box 276)
  - #1207 Yale megaphone, 1928 (Box 278)
  - #1208 Class of 1944 banners (Box 273)
  - #1209 Carved tabletop from John Boogher, ex-student from the Class of 1905, undated
  - #1210 Tankard of Earle R. Whipple, Class of 1904, circa 1901 (Box 253)
  - #1211 Class of 1947's 55th reunion badge, 2002 (Box 274)
  - #1212 China bowl given to Dr. Marvin stevens, Lt. Commander, USN, for his part in the rescue of American Prisoners at Japanese Camp #17, and his role in accepting the surrender of Japan, 1945 (Box 259)
  - #1213 Ceramic mug with signatures of the members of the Class of 1898, Sheffield Scientific School, made by Philo King, 1897 (Box 258)
  - #1214 Yale College Class of 1954 pennant (Box 261)
  - #1215 Door lock and key from the wine cellar of the Sheffield Mansion, 1832 (Box 260)
  - #1216 Memorabilia of Frank O' Reilly, Jr, 1933-1936 (Box 254)
  - #1217 Polo Championship badges, Psi Upsilon (Fence Club) badge, Cannon & Castle Society badge, circa 1929 (Box 257)
  - #1218 Plaque removed from room (probably in Connecticut Hall) stating occupancy by James Kent, Class of 1781, Yale College, undated (Box 266)
  - #1219 Skull and Bones Flag/banner, circa 1930 (Box 267)
  - #1220 Yale banner and pennants belonging to Francis White (1913S), undated (Box 277)
  - #1221 Lenox China. Porcelain ashtry of the Yale Bowl by F. J. Cutherbertson for Lenox, undated (Box 262)
  - #1222 Psi Upsilon gavel presented to Robert Lee Luce (yc, 1889), 1913 (Box 263)
  - #1223 Buttons and patches from Yale College, Class of 1940, 50th anniversary, 1990 (Box 298)
  - #1224 Yale Alumni Society certificate, 1896 (Box 113)
  - #1225 Yale/Harvard footbal game ticket, 1913 (Box 113)
  - #1226 Sheffield Scientific School, Class of 1881 flag (Box 300)
  - #1227 Female doll wearing Yale cheerleading uniform, undated (Box 298)
  - #1228 Yale notebook, circa 1933 (Box 266)
  - #1229 Medical Institution of Yale College, Connecticut Medical Society, 1810-1884 Copper medal with blue ribbon, 1913 (Box 104C, Folder 303)
  - #1230 U.S. Olympians Las Vegas Trianthlon pin, gift to A. Bartlett Giamatti, 1984 (Box 301, Folder 1)
  - #1231 U.S. Olympians Las Vegas Trianthlon t-shirt, gift to A. Bartlett Giamatti, 1984 (Box 301, Folder 1)
  - #1232 Triathlete Magazine, 1984 September (Box 301, Folder 1)
  - #1233 Plaque presented to A. Bartlett Giamatti by the American Association of Teachers of Spanish and Portugese, 1985 (Box 301, Folder 2)
  - #1234 Clippings and printed material documenting A. Bartlett Giamatti speech at University of Georgia Bicentennial Celebration, 1985 (Box 301, Folder 3)
  - #1235 Wall hanging given to A. Bartlett Giamatti from Dr. and Mrs. Frederick F. Chien (Box 301)
  - #1236 Scrapbook of Star of the Sea Convent, St. James Cape, South Africa, given to A. Bartlett Giamatti, 1986 (Box 301)
  - #1237 Wooden carving [head of Jesus Christ?] given to A. Bartlett Giamatti (Box 301)
  - #1238 Gold pocket watch commemorating Yale football team's 1980 Ivy League championship, inscribed "A Bartlett Giamatti '60'" given to A. Bartlett Giamatti (Box 301)
  - #1239 Metal door hardware, undated (Box 223)
  - #1240 Wooden ladies fan autographed by Yale students, circa 1899 (Box 303)
  - #1241 Child Study Center 75th anniversary button, 1986 (Box 304)
  - #1242 Athletic medals of Walter S. Kimball (1934) (Box 304)
  - #1243 Class of 1909 banner, circa 1909 (Box 305)
  - #1244 Metal box with writing "Yale College" "The Mrs. Hepsa Ely Silliman Memorial", undated (Box 306)
  - #1245 Osborne Halle porcelain vase, undated (Box 307)
  - #1246 Wooden cane with silver tip; inscribed "Yale '94", circa 1894 (Box 308)
  - #1247 Knotted wooden walking cane, circa 1894 (Box 308)
  - #1248 Class of 1928 banner, circa 1928 (Box 309)
  - #1249 Class of 1918 banner, circa 1918 (Box 309)
  - #1250 Yale bicentennial celebration poster, 1901 (Box 309)
  - #1251 Large two-handled (one broken) brown pottery Yale cup, that belonged to Charles P. Howland, Class of 1891,with many autographs of classmates including Harvey Cushing., circa 1908-1909 (Box 310)
    Scope and Contents
    May have been autographed at a DKE fraternity dinner at the Waldorf, NYC.
  - #1252 DKE Fraternity paddle that belonged to David Howland, Class of 1933. "From Jack Winter.", circa 1932 (Box 311)
  - #1253 Yale lambskin belonging to Charles Franklin Bliss, Class of 1880, circa 1880 (Box 319)
  - #1254 Yale Co-op money bag, undated (Box 320)
  - #1255 Library china (Box 280–297)
  - #1256 Certificate awarded to Miss Rose Weiss for participation in the pageant held on the two-hundredth anniversary of the removal of Yale College to New Haven, 1916 October 21 (Box 321)
  - #1257 Yale Daily News pin, 1912, previously owned by William C. Bullitt, Yale 1913 (Box 322)
  - #1258 Yale-Princeton debate pin, 1911, previously owned by William C. Bullitt, Yale 1913 (Box 322)
  - #1259 Yale Debating Association pin, 1912, previously owned by William C. Bullitt, Yale 1913 (Box 322)
  - #1260 Yale Dramatic Association pin, 1912, previously owned by William C. Bullitt, Yale 1913 (Box 322)
  - #1261 Psi Upsilon fraternity paddle presented to Edmund Pendleton Livingston (1888-1972), Yale College 1911, 1908 November 24 (Box 323)
  - #1262 Two pewter book cradles from the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library. Original cradles for the Guttenberg Bible., Undated (Box 324–325)
  - #1263 Oil painting of Sterling Memorial Library Librarian's Courtyard by Theresa Garrett Eliot, Circa 1930s (Box 326)
  - Stained Glass Windows removed from Calhoun and Branford Colleges
    - Branford College
      Windows were made by G. Owen Bonawit Inc. in New York, 1933.
      - From living room, Branford House
        - #1264: stained glass window (cook) (Box 352)
        - #1266: stained glass window (hunter) (Box 354)
      - Original location uncertain
        - #1265: stained glass window (two men in field) (Box 353)
    - Calhoun College
      Windows were made by d'Ascenzo Studios in Philaelphia, 1933.
      - From Common Room
        - #1267: stained glass window (1782) (Box 355)
          General
          Year of John C. Calhoun's birth.
        - #1268: stained glass window (1850) (Box 356)
          Year of John C. Calhoun's death.
        - #1270: stained glass window (South Carolina seal, side one) (Box 358)
        - #1272: stained glass window (Great Seal of the United States) (Box 360)
        - #1275: stained glass window (man in top hat) (Box 363)
          Lower, replaced section of window originally bore the inscription "John C. Calhoun, Farmer, entered Yale 1802".
        - #1276: stained glass window (John C. Calhoun) (Box 364)
          Lower, replaced section originally bore the inscription "1782-1850 Statesman" and had a kneeling African American figure.
      - From Dining Hall
        - #1269: stained glass window (banjo player) (Box 357)
        - #1271: stained glass window (woman in front of cabin) (Box 359)
          Window was titled "Slave Cabin" in original sketch.
        - #1273: stained glass window (house in woods) (Box 361)
          Window was titled "House at Fort Hill" in original sketch; Fort Hill was Calhoun's house in Clemson, South Carolina.
        - #1274: stained glass window (log cabin on pilings) (Box 362)
          Window was titled "Gin House" in original sketch.
  - #1277: Four color prints on silk, of athletes from crew, baseball, track, and hockey with Yale insignia; issued by Murad Cigarettes, New York, Circa 1910 (Box 365)
  - Library Lounge silver and glassware
    - #1278: Tureen with lid, silver, Undated (Box 367)
    - #1279: Teapot with warmer, silver, Undated (Box 368)
    - #1280: Large ladle, silver, Undated (Box 369)
    - #1281: Shallow footed bowl, silver, Undated (Box 369)
    - #1282: Deep footed bowl with handles, engraved with initials, silver, Undated (Box 369)
    - #1283: Teapot, silver, Undated (Box 370)
    - #1284-1285: Two small 3-arm candelabra, silver, Undated (Box 370)
    - #1286: Footed basket, silver, Undated (Box 371)
    - #1287-1288: Two creamers with attached base, silver, Undated (Box 371)
    - #1289: Coffeepot, silver, Undated (Box 371)
    - #1290: Coffeepot, silver, Undated (Box 372)
    - #1291: Coffeepot with engraved initials, silver, Undated (Box 372)
    - #11292-1293: Two ornate candlesticks, silver, Undated (Box 372)
    - #1294: Set of nine silver sugar shell spoons in roll, Undated (Box 372)
    - #1295: Rectangular dish with handles and ornate floral border, silver, Undated (Box 373)
    - #1296: Shallow footed bowl with handles, engraved with MLB, silver, Undated (Box 373)
    - #1297: Oval plate, silver, Undated (Box 374)
    - #1298: Oval basket, silver, Undated (Box 374)
    - #1299: plate engraved with K·L·T and W·H·O, silver, Undated (Box 374)
    - #1300: Oval plate on small feet, silver, Undated (Box 374)
    - #1301: Shallow bowl, silver, Undated (Box 374)
    - #1302-1303: Two large 3-arm candelabra, silver, Undated (Box 375)
    - #1304: Two-handled cup, silver, Undated (Box 376)
    - #1305: Tall beverage dispenser with lid, silver, Undated (Box 376)
    - #1306: Platter engraved with K·L·T and W·H·O, silver, Undated (Box 377)
    - #1307: Engraved platter with handles, silver, Undated (Box 377)
    - #1308: Large platter with handles, silver, Undated (Box 378)
    - #1309: Roaster lid, electroplated (no base), Undated (Box 379)
    - #1310: Compote bowl, silver, Undated (Box 380)
    - #1311: Round bowl, silver, Undated (Box 381)
    - #1312: Condiment server, silver (no dishes), Undated (Box 381)
    - #1313: Small condiment server, silver (no dishes), Undated (Box 381)
    - #1314: Server with central handle and five openwork "goblets" that sit on pegs, silver, Undated (Box 381)
    - #1315: Small oval cranberry glass bowl with one handle, gold trim, Undated (Box 382)
    - #1316: Small round cranberry glass bowl with gold filigree (1 of 2), Undated (Box 383)
    - #1317: Small round cranberry glass bowl with gold filigree (2 of 2), Undated (Box 384)
    - #1318: Cranberry glass compote dish, Undated (Box 385)
    - #1319: Set of three blue and white ceramic plates, Cremona, Undated (Box 386)
    - #1320: Round shallow bowl, silver, Undated (Box 387)
    - #1321: Serving bowl on tall stem, bas relief medallion in center, silver, Undated (Box 387)
    - #1322: Oval platter with raised center section, silver, Undated (Box 387)
    - #1323: Three pieces of chafing dish, silver, Undated (Box 387)
    - #1324: Box of miscellaneous pieces, possibly for chafing dish, Undated (Box 387)
    - #1325: Platter with tree design in counter-relief, silver, Undated (Box 388)
    - #1326: Roll of silverware pieces, including nut crackers, Undated (Box 389)
    - #1327: Coffeepot, engraved with B, silver, Undated (Box 389)
    - #1328: Round lid with handle, silver (no base), Undated (Box 389)
    - #1329: Oval bowl, silver (missing base attachment), Undated (Box 389)